<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Grant Hurley</title>
    <link>http://www.granthurley.ca/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Grant Hurley</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2017 11:05:13 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.granthurley.ca/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Synthesis Statements on Open Government and Archives and Records Management</title>
      <link>http://www.granthurley.ca/blog/three-synthesis-statements-on-open-government-and-archives-and-records-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2017 11:05:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.granthurley.ca/blog/three-synthesis-statements-on-open-government-and-archives-and-records-management/</guid>
      <description>As the InterPARES Trust project starts to wrap up, it has provided an occaison to reflect on the five years of work (!) that was completed. I was priveleged to work as a research assistant and later research consultant (i.e. pro bono post-graduation) on project NA08: &amp;ldquo;The Implications of Open Government, Open Data, and Big Data on the Management of Digital Records in an Online Environment.&amp;rdquo; NA08 included some fantastic people and inspirational professionals: Valerie Léveillé, John McDonald, Kelly Rovegno, Jim Suderman, and Kat Timms, who produced an impressive body of papers and insights from this project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes From the ACA Screening of Stories We Tell</title>
      <link>http://www.granthurley.ca/blog/notes-from-the-aca-screening-of-stories-we-tell/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 11:44:22 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.granthurley.ca/blog/notes-from-the-aca-screening-of-stories-we-tell/</guid>
      <description>At the recent ACA conference in Ottawa, I had the wonderful opportunity to host a screening of one of my favorite films - Sarah Polley&amp;rsquo;s 2012 documentary Stories We Tell. I&amp;rsquo;ve long been convinced that this film has a lot to say about archives. It’s a film fundamentally concerned with how we understand the past through the contradictions of memory and the opaque borders shared between memories and what has been recorded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking &#39;Collaboration&#39; from Buzzword to Action: A Take on the AAO 2017 Conference</title>
      <link>http://www.granthurley.ca/blog/taking-collaboration-from-buzzword-to-action-a-take-on-the-aao-2017-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 21:06:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.granthurley.ca/blog/taking-collaboration-from-buzzword-to-action-a-take-on-the-aao-2017-conference/</guid>
      <description>A conference swag item was this coaster with embedded flower seeds. Quite a nice metaphor, no?   Though I’ve been a volunteer for the Archives Association of Ontario since late 2015, I finally had the chance to attend my first AAO conference last month at the Faculty of Information at the University of Toronto. I’d long heard that the AAO conference is one that is firmly devoted to archival practice, and this edition (the 14th since 2004!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World &amp; Situating Myself</title>
      <link>http://www.granthurley.ca/blog/hello-world--situating-myself/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 16:02:31 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.granthurley.ca/blog/hello-world--situating-myself/</guid>
      <description>In the tradition of &amp;lsquo;hello world&amp;rsquo; posts everywhere, I&amp;rsquo;d like to begin this blog by greeting anyone out there in internet land, particularly archives-and-libraries-on-the-internet-land. This blog is a place to hold my thoughts, to write out a problem or question that&amp;rsquo;s been nagging me, and to report on the successes and failures of my work. I&amp;rsquo;m especially interested in interrogating questions in archival theory and practice, and particularly, in digital preservation and related areas of study.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grant Hurley | Résumé</title>
      <link>http://www.granthurley.ca/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 15:52:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.granthurley.ca/resume/</guid>
      <description>Current Role  Digital Preservation Librarian, Scholars Portal, Ontario Council of University Libraries/University of Toronto  Current Committee &amp;amp; Service Roles Canadian Association of Research Libraries (CARL), Digital Preservation Working Group (2017-present)
- Lead, Survey Subgroup
Canadian General Standards Board, Committee on Electronic Records and Image Management (2017-Present)
- Association of Canadian Archivists Representative (voting member)
Canadian Research Knowledge Network (CRKN) Trusted Digital Repository Task Group (2017-Present)
- Co-lead, Service Model and Certification Subgroup</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grant Hurley | Research</title>
      <link>http://www.granthurley.ca/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 08:48:30 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.granthurley.ca/research/</guid>
      <description>Research Interests: I am interested in a bunch of things relating to archives and libraries, including: making digital preservation accessible and actionable; digital preservation standards and certification; open government, open data, and citizen engagement; and subjects relating to archival theory and practice more broadly, such as community archives and decolonization.
Peer-Reviewed Articles Hurley, G. (2017). Your comments here: Contextualizing technologies, seeking records and supporting transparency for citizen engagement. Tidsskriftet Arkiv, 8(1), 1-25.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grant Hurley | About</title>
      <link>http://www.granthurley.ca/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 16:16:04 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.granthurley.ca/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello. I am an archivist and librarian. I work as the Digital Preservation Librarian for Scholars Portal, the information technology service for the Ontario Council of University Libraries. I am responsible for overseeing the preservation of shared licenced content content, such as journals and books, and developing, maintaining and supporting services to enable our members preserve their own unique digital assets. These include the Scholars Portal Trustworthy Digital Repository and the Permafrost digital preservation service, and developing new services in emerging areas to meet our members&amp;rsquo; needs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>