<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Grant Hurley</title>
    <link>https://gehurley.github.io/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Grant Hurley</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 15:52:50 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://gehurley.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>resume</title>
      <link>https://gehurley.github.io/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 15:52:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gehurley.github.io/resume/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;current-roles&#34;&gt;Current Roles&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Digital Preservation Librarian, &lt;a href=&#34;http://scholarsportal.info&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Scholars Portal&lt;/a&gt;, Ontario Council of University Libraries/University of Toronto&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Director Without Portfolio 2 &amp;amp; Editor, &lt;em&gt;Off the Record&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aao-archivists.ca&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Archives Association of Ontario&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ex Officio Director and Alcuin Book Design Awards Catalogue Project Manager, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.alcuinsociety.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Alcuin Society&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Researcher, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.interparestrust.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;InterPARES Trust&lt;/a&gt;, University of British Columbia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;education&#34;&gt;Education&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2012 - 2015 &amp;mdash; Dual Master of Archival Studies and Master of Library and Information Studies. University of British Columbia. Vancouver, British Columbia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2010 - 2012 &amp;mdash; Master of Arts in English. University of British Columbia. Vancouver, British Columbia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2006 - 2010 &amp;mdash; Bachelor of Arts in English (First Class Honours). Mount Allison University. Sackville, New Brunswick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;past-work&#34;&gt;Past Work&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;August 2015 - July 2016 &amp;mdash; Records Analyst and Archivist for The College of Physicians and Surgeons of Ontario&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;December 2014 &amp;mdash; Student Intern at the City of Toronto Archives&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May - August 2014 &amp;mdash; Co-op Student, Records Management and Library, Teck Resources Ltd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;January - April, 2014 &amp;mdash; Special Collections Project Assistant, University of British Columbia Okanagan Library&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May - August, 2013 &amp;mdash; Student Librarian, BGC Engineering&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May 2012 - December 2014 &amp;ndash; Curatorial and Informatics Assistant, Beaty Biodiversity Museum, University of British Columbia&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;past-volunteer-and-committee-roles&#34;&gt;Past Volunteer and Committee Roles&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014-2016 &amp;mdash; Blog Editor, BookTraces project, University of Virginia&lt;br /&gt;
2014-2015 &amp;mdash; ARMA Representative, ACA UBC Student Chapter&lt;br /&gt;
2013 &amp;mdash; Treasurer, ACA UBC Student Chapter&lt;br /&gt;
2012-2013 &amp;mdash; First Year Representative, ACA UBC Student Chapter&lt;br /&gt;
2012 &amp;mdash; Conference Co-Chair, Endnotes Graduate Conference in English, University of British Columbia&lt;br /&gt;
2011-12 &amp;mdash; ACCUTE Representative, UBC Department of English Graduate Caucus&lt;br /&gt;
2009-10 &amp;mdash; Vice President, Board of Directors, CHMA Community Radio&lt;br /&gt;
2009-10 &amp;mdash; President, English Society, Mount Allison University&lt;br /&gt;
2009 &amp;mdash; Student Representative, Post-Doctoral Fellow Search Committee, Canadian Studies. Mount Allison University.&lt;br /&gt;
2008-10 &amp;mdash; Editor, 7 Mondays, Mount Allison University&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;teaching&#34;&gt;Teaching&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Teaching Assistant, ENGL 110: Approaches to Literature. University of British Columbia. Fall 2010, Winter 2011, Fall 2011, Winter 2012.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Course Intern, ENGL 1801: Introduction to Prose Fiction. Mount Allison University. Fall 2009&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;awards-and-grants&#34;&gt;Awards and Grants&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015 &amp;mdash; Association of Canadian Archivists Gordon Dodds Prize &lt;input class=&#34;MyButton&#34; type=&#34;button&#34; value=&#34;media&#34;onclick=&#34;window.open(&#39;http://slais.ubc.ca/grant-hurley-wins-the-gordon-dodds-award/&#39;, &#39;_blank&#39;)&#34;/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
2015 &amp;mdash; Arts Co-op Student of the Year &lt;input class=&#34;MyButton&#34; type=&#34;button&#34; value=&#34;media&#34;onclick=&#34;window.open(&#39;http://artscoop.ubc.ca/2015/03/16/grant-hurley/&#39;, &#39;_blank&#39;)&#34;/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
2014 &amp;mdash; Student to Association of Canadian Archivists conference travel award&lt;br /&gt;
2013 &amp;mdash; ARMA International Education Fund Rita Holt Scholarship&lt;br /&gt;
2013 &amp;mdash; O’Brien Foundation Fellowship &lt;input class=&#34;MyButton&#34; type=&#34;button&#34; value=&#34;media&#34;onclick=&#34;window.open(&#39;http://www.obrienfoundation.ca/en/o-brien-fellows/where-are-they-now/270-grant-hurley-2013&#39;, &#39;_blank&#39;)&#34;/&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
2012 &amp;mdash; CLA/ACB Dafoe Scholarship, Canadian Library Association&lt;br /&gt;
2010 &amp;mdash; SSHRC Joseph-Armand Bombardier Canada Graduate Scholarship&lt;br /&gt;
2010 &amp;mdash; Allison Watson Beveridge Prize, Mount Allison University&lt;br /&gt;
2009 &amp;mdash; Crake Summer Undergraduate Research Fellowship, Mount Allison University&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>research</title>
      <link>https://gehurley.github.io/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 08:48:30 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gehurley.github.io/research/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Research Interests:&lt;/strong&gt; I am interested in a bunch of things relating to archives and libraries, including: making digital preservation accessible and actionable; digital preservation standards and certification; open government, open data, and citizen engagement; and subjects relating to archival theory and practice more broadly, such as community archives and decolonization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;peer-reviewed-articles&#34;&gt;Peer-Reviewed Articles&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hurley, G. (2017). Your comments here: Contextualizing technologies, seeking records and supporting transparency for citizen engagement. &lt;em&gt;Tidsskriftet Arkiv&lt;/em&gt;, 8(1), 1-25. doi: 10.7577/ta.1956 &lt;input class=&#34;MyButton&#34; type=&#34;button&#34; value=&#34;Open Access&#34;onclick=&#34;window.open(&#39;https://journals.hioa.no/index.php/arkiv/article/view/1956&#39;, &#39;_blank&#39;)&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hurley, G. (2016). Community archives, community clouds: Enabling digital preservation for small archives. &lt;em&gt;Archivaria&lt;/em&gt;, 82, 129-150. &lt;input class=&#34;MyButton&#34; type=&#34;button&#34; value=&#34;Closed Access&#34;onclick=&#34;window.open(&#39;http://archivaria.ca/index.php/archivaria/article/view/13561&#39;, &#39;_blank&#39;)&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hurley, G. (2015). Student publications at UBC&amp;rsquo;s School of Library, Archival and Information Studies: An anecdotal bibliography. &lt;em&gt;See Also&lt;/em&gt;, 1(1), 1-9. &lt;input class=&#34;MyButton&#34; type=&#34;button&#34; value=&#34;Open Access&#34;onclick=&#34;window.open(&#39;http://ojs.library.ubc.ca/index.php/seealso/article/view/186339&#39;, &#39;_blank&#39;)&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Szabo, I., Hurley, G., Cavaghan, S., &amp;amp; Irwin, D. E. (2014). A call for the preservation of images, recordings, and other data in association with avian genetic samples, and the introduction of a solution: OMBIRDS. &lt;em&gt;The Auk&lt;/em&gt;, 131(3), 321-326. doi: 10.1642/AUK-13-237.1 &lt;input class=&#34;MyButton&#34; type=&#34;button&#34; value=&#34;Closed Access&#34;onclick=&#34;window.open(&#39;http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.1642/AUK-13-237.1&#39;, &#39;_blank&#39;)&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;book-chapters&#34;&gt;Book Chapters&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hurley, G. (2015). Archival reappraisal. In L. Duranti &amp;amp; P. Franks (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Encyclopedia of Archival Science&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 80-82). Lanham, MD: Rowman &amp;amp; Littlefield. &lt;input class=&#34;MyButton&#34; type=&#34;button&#34; value=&#34;Google Books&#34;onclick=&#34;window.open(&#39;https://books.google.ca/books?id=ryT-CQAAQBAJ&amp;lpg=PP1&amp;pg=PA80#v=onepage&amp;q&amp;f=false&#39;, &#39;_blank&#39;)&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hurley, G. (2011). Money is time: Case studies in small Canadian regional archives. In K. Garay &amp;amp; C. Verduyn (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Archival narratives for Canada: Re-telling stories in a changing landscape&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 98-113). Halifax: Fernwood. &lt;input class=&#34;MyButton&#34; type=&#34;button&#34; value=&#34;Publisher&#34;onclick=&#34;window.open(&#39;https://fernwoodpublishing.ca/book/archival-narratives-for-canada&#39;, &#39;_blank&#39;)&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;conference-proceedings&#34;&gt;Conference Proceedings&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;McLelland, R., Hackett, Y., Hurley, G., &amp;amp; Collins, D. (2014). Agreements between cloud service providers and their clients: A review of contract terms. Proceedings from 2nd Annual Conference of the International Council on Archives. 11th-15th October, 2014. Girona, Spain. &lt;input class=&#34;MyButton&#34; type=&#34;button&#34; value=&#34;Open Access&#34;onclick=&#34;window.open(&#39;http://www.girona.cat/web/ica2014/ponents/textos/id210.pdf&#39;, &#39;_blank&#39;)&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;reports&#34;&gt;Reports&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hurley, G., Léveillé V., &amp;amp; McDonald, J. (2016). Managing records of citizen engagement initiatives: A primer. Vancouver, BC: InterPARES Trust. &lt;input class=&#34;MyButton&#34; type=&#34;button&#34; value=&#34;Open Access&#34;onclick=&#34;window.open(&#39;https://interparestrust.org/assets/public/dissemination/NA08_20161001_ManagingRecordsCitizenEngagement_Primer_Final.pdf&#39;, &#39;_blank&#39;)&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;McLelland, R., Hurley G., &amp;amp; Collins, D. (2016). Contract terms with cloud service providers. Vancouver, BC: InterPARES Trust. &lt;input class=&#34;MyButton&#34; type=&#34;button&#34; value=&#34;Open Access&#34;onclick=&#34;window.open(&#39;https://interparestrust.org/assets/public/dissemination/NA10_20160130_ContractTerms_InternationalPlenary3_FinalReport_Final.pdf&#39;, &#39;_blank&#39;)&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;theses&#34;&gt;Theses&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hurley, G. (2012). The lyric west: Reading the Vancouver Poetry Society, 1916-1974. (Unpublished master of arts dissertation). University of British Columbia, Vancouver, British Columbia. &lt;input class=&#34;MyButton&#34; type=&#34;button&#34; value=&#34;Open Access&#34;onclick=&#34;window.open(&#39;https://open.library.ubc.ca/cIRcle/collections/ubctheses/24/items/1.0072770&#39;, &#39;_blank&#39;)&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hurley, G. (2010). Coming of age: Canadian children’s literature and national identities, 1900-1945 (Unpublished bachelor of arts dissertation). Mount Allison University, Sackville, New Brunswick. &lt;input class=&#34;MyButton&#34; type=&#34;button&#34; value=&#34;Open Access&#34;onclick=&#34;window.open(&#39;/grant/pdf/Hurley-ComingOfAge.pdf&#39;, &#39;_blank&#39;)&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;posters-paper-presentations&#34;&gt;Posters &amp;amp; Paper Presentations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Davis, K. &amp;amp; Hurley, G. (2017). eBooks preservation at Scholars Portal. eBooks and the Academic Library Market: The Charlotte Initiative Open Conference. 9-10 March, 2017. Charlotte, North Carolina.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leahey, A. &amp;amp; Hurley, G. (2017). Developing integrated workflows for data curation and preservation in libraries. 12th International Digital Curation Conference. 20-23 February, 2017. Edinburgh, Scotland. &lt;input class=&#34;MyButton&#34; type=&#34;button&#34; value=&#34;Poster&#34;onclick=&#34;window.open(&#39;http://www.dcc.ac.uk/sites/default/files/documents/IDCC17~/41_Developing_Integrated_Workflows.pdf&#39;, &#39;_blank&#39;)&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hurley, G. (2016). Digital participation wanted: Seeking records and supporting transparency for technology-driven citizen engagement. InterPARES Trust International Symposium. 9 December, 2016. Victoria University of Wellington, Wellington, New Zealand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hurley, G. (2016). Contextualizing Technologies for Citizen Engagement: Seeking Records and Supporting Transparency. Trust and Transparency in E-Government International Conference. 26 October, 2016. Høgskolen i Oslo og Akershus, Oslo, Norway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hurley, G. (2016). The long-term preservation of digital records and information. 7th Annual Information Management Session, Federation of Medical Regulatory Authorities of Canada. 11 June, 2016. Banff, Alberta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hurley, G. (2013). Determining a signature B.C. wine grape. UBC iSchool Visual Analytics Class Poster Session. 26 November, 2013. University of British Columbia, Vancouver, British Columbia. &lt;input class=&#34;MyButton&#34; type=&#34;button&#34; value=&#34;Poster&#34; onclick=&#34;window.open(&#39;/grant/pdf/Hurley-BCWineGrape.pdf&#39;, &#39;_blank&#39;)&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hurley, G. (2013). Reconciling the archive: Library and Archives Canada versus the Truth and Reconciliation Commission. Endnotes Graduate Conference in English. 11-12 May, 2013. University of British Columbia, Vancouver, British Columbia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hurley, G. (2011). Seth and Canadian archival narrative. Association of Canadian College and University Teachers in English Conference. 28-31 May, 2011. Congress of Social Sciences and Humanities, Fredericton, New Brunswick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hurley, G. (2010). ‘Work at Home&amp;rsquo;: Gender and Nation in Canadian children’s fiction, 1830-1900. Second Annual Latin American and Latino/a Studies Conference. 12 April, 2010. Bowling Green State University, Bowling Green, Ohio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hurley, G. (2009). Money is time: Case studies in regional archives. Third Biennial Archives in Canada Conference: Archives and the Canadian Narrative. 10-12 June, 2009. Mount Allison University, Sackville, New Brunswick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;invited-talks-lectures&#34;&gt;Invited Talks &amp;amp; Lectures&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Preserving Digital Things: Projects, Plans and Debates in 2017.&amp;rdquo; For HIST 4851: Introduction to Archival Science, Lakehead University. Thunder Bay, Ontario. March 31, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Digital Preservation 2067: Keeping Our Digital Memory from Here on Out.&amp;rdquo; Northwestern Ontario Archivists&amp;rsquo; Association. Thunder Bay, Ontario. March 30, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Professional Panel on Digital Archives participant. Association of Canadian Archivists, University of Toronto Student Chapter. Toronto, Ontario. January 24, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;exhibitions-history-projects&#34;&gt;Exhibitions &amp;amp; History Projects&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;150th Anniversary of the College of Physicians and Surgeons of Ontario. 28-29 May, 2016 for Doors Open Toronto and online. The College of Physicians and Surgeons of Ontario, Toronto, Ontario. &lt;input class=&#34;MyButton&#34; type=&#34;button&#34; value=&#34;Website&#34;onclick=&#34;window.open(&#39;http://www.cpso.on.ca/About-Us/A-Look-Back&#39;, &#39;_blank&#39;)&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Settling the language: Dictionaries and language change, 1490 to today. 3 June - 15 August, 2015. Rare Books and Special Collections, University of British Columbia. &lt;input class=&#34;MyButton&#34; type=&#34;button&#34; value=&#34;Catalogue&#34;onclick=&#34;window.open(&#39;http://rbsc-03feb2015.sites.olt.ubc.ca/files/2015/06/Catalogue.pdf&#39;, &#39;_blank&#39;)&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first Roman Catholic chuch and cemetery, 1825-1859. St. Andrews, New Brunswick: Church of Saint Andrew, 2010. &lt;input class=&#34;MyButton&#34; type=&#34;button&#34; value=&#34;Brochure&#34; onclick=&#34;window.open(&#39;/grant/pdf/Hurley-FirstRomanCatholicCemetery.pdf&#39;, &#39;_blank&#39;)&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>https://gehurley.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 16:16:04 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gehurley.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://gehurley.github.io/img/hurley2.jpg&#34; class=&#34;me&#34; alt=&#34;Grant Hurley&#34; align=&#34;right&#34;;&gt; Hello. I am an archivist and librarian. I currently work as the Digital Preservation Librarian for Scholars Portal, a service of the Ontario Council of University Libraries. OCUL is a 21-member consortium of academic libraries in Ontario. In this role, I am responsible for supporting the preservation of shared licenced content content such as ejournals and books and helping our members preserve their own digital assets. I oversee developing and maintaing services and projects, research issues and questions, keep on top of digital preservation happenings, design and implement workflows, and consult on licencing issues. I also serve as Director without Portfolio and &lt;em&gt;Off the Record&lt;/em&gt; Editor with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aao-archivists.ca&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Archives Association of Ontario&lt;/a&gt;, as an Ex Officio Director and Book Design Awards Catalogue Project Manager for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.alcuinsociety.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Alcuin Society&lt;/a&gt;, and as a researcher with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.interparestrust.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;InterPARES Trust&lt;/a&gt; project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started my career as a summer archives assistant at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://ccarchives.ca&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Charlotte County Archives&lt;/a&gt; in my hometown of St. Andrews, New Brunswick. I was 16 and it was my first real summer job - and it turns out, led to my career! I returned to the Archives for three summers after that, and in that time, fell in love with the exciting and dynamic work that happens in archives on a daily basis. After pursuing a research interest in Canadian literature through a BA and MA, I completed the Dual Master of Archival Studies and Master of Library and Information Studies program at the University of British Columbia in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outside of my work, I love to cook up big meals, shake up cocktails, collect Canadian music of the 1960s and 70s, go on hikes, and read thick books. I&amp;rsquo;ve been slowly working through WSET certification levels in wine knowledge, so hit me with your wine questions in addition to your archival ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;articles-on-my-work&#34;&gt;Articles on my Work&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www1.toronto.ca/City%20Of%20Toronto/City%20Clerks/Toronto%20Archives/PDFs/Archives%20annual%20report%202014.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Grant Hurley and the Kent Family fonds&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
2015 article on my work experience at the City of Toronto Archives for their 2014 Annual Report&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://artscoop.ubc.ca/2015/03/16/grant-hurley/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;2014 UBC iSchool (SLAIS MAS Co-op Student of the Year&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 2014 article on my work experience at Teck Resources Ltd. and UBC Arts Co-op Award&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://okanaganlife.com/ubc0-celebrates-opening-of-special-collections-room/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;UBC Celebrates Opening of Special Collections Room&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
2014 article describing my work settiung up UBC Okanagan&amp;rsquo;s Special Collections&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.winesandvines.com/template.cfm?section=news&amp;content=126744&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Surprise: It&amp;rsquo;s Riesling and Syrah - Analysis points to British Columbia&amp;rsquo;s Candidates for Signature Grapes&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
2014 article on my UBC &lt;a href=&#34;https://gehurley.github.io/pdf/Hurley-BCWineGrape.pdf&#34;&gt;visual analytics class project&lt;/a&gt; to identify BC&amp;rsquo;s signature wine grapes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://beatymuseum.ubc.ca/2013/11/20/cowan-tetrapod-collection-databases-have-evolved/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Cowan Tetrapod Databases Have Evolved!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
2012 article on my work with the Beaty Biodiversity Museum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;writing&#34;&gt;Writing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;archives-association-of-ontario&#34;&gt;Archives Association of Ontario&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I write regular items and an editorial for &lt;em&gt;Off the Record&lt;/em&gt;, the newsletter of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aao-archivists.ca&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Archives Association of Ontario:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current Issues (Members Only)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://aao-archivists.ca/page-18317&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;33.1 - Winter 2017&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ldquo;Message from the Editor&amp;rdquo; &amp;amp; &amp;ldquo;Archives in Fiction: &lt;em&gt;Consolation&lt;/em&gt; (2006)&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://aao-archivists.ca/page-18317&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;32.3 - Summer 2016&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ldquo;Message from the Editor&amp;rdquo; &amp;amp; &amp;ldquo;Food in the Archives: The Labatt Collection&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://aao-archivists.ca/page-18317&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;32.2 - Spring 2016&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ldquo;Message from the Editor&amp;rdquo; &amp;amp; &amp;ldquo;Food in the Archives: Cooking with Hannah Glasse&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open Issues&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://goo.gl/QCAHlo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;32.4 - Fall 2016 - Special Issue on Archives and Indigenous Issues&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ldquo;Message from the Editor&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B9Z2lQjrgs_5ejhnVXdpb1hJZlE/view&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;32.1 - Winter 2016&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ldquo;Message from the Editor&amp;rdquo; &amp;amp; &amp;ldquo;Food in the Archives: Benson&amp;rsquo;s Strong Ale&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-alcuin-society&#34;&gt;The Alcuin Society&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blog&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I write regularly for the Alcuin Society on book arts, book design, and book collecting &lt;a href=&#34;http://alcuinsociety.com/author/ghurley/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amphora&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hurley, G. (2014). Book Traces: Preserving bibliodiversity. &lt;em&gt;Amphora&lt;/em&gt; 168: 23-24.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;miscellaneous&#34;&gt;Miscellaneous&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vancouver notables: Book artist Emma Lehto. January 6, 2014. &lt;em&gt;Sad Mag&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://archive.sadmag.ca/news/2014/01/vancouver-notables-destructive-book-artist-emma-lehto/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dispatches: Kombucha 101 at Homesteader&amp;rsquo;s Emporium. November 16, 2013. &lt;em&gt;Sad Mag&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://archive.sadmag.ca/news/2013/11/dispatches-kombucha-101-at-homesteaders-emporium/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vancouver notables: Rick Havlak. November 2, 2013. &lt;em&gt;Sad Mag&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://archive.sadmag.ca/news/2013/11/vancouver-notables-rick-havlak/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World &amp; Situating Myself</title>
      <link>https://gehurley.github.io/blog/hello-world--situating-myself/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 16:02:31 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gehurley.github.io/blog/hello-world--situating-myself/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the tradition of &amp;lsquo;hello world&amp;rsquo; posts everywhere, I&amp;rsquo;d like to begin this blog by greeting anyone out there in internet land, particularly archives-and-libraries-on-the-internet-land. This blog is a place to hold my thoughts, to write out a problem or question that&amp;rsquo;s been nagging me, and to report on the successes and failures of my work. I&amp;rsquo;m especially interested in interrogating questions in archival theory and practice, and particularly, in digital preservation and related areas of study. I&amp;rsquo;m interested in lots of things relating to these fields, which you can find links to &lt;a href=&#34;https://gehurley.github.io/research/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently had the pleasure of reading Erin Wunker&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Notes from a Feminist Killjoy: Essays on Everyday Life&lt;/em&gt; (BookThug, 2016). In her introduction, Wunker describes the importance of accounting for one&amp;rsquo;s situated knowlege, an intention cited from scholar Donna Haraway. &amp;ldquo;Situating yourself enacts the deliberate practice of locating your own identity and experiences as coming from somewhere and being mediated by certain things such as your race, gender and class,&amp;rdquo; Wunker writes, &amp;ldquo;Laying these things out for yourself locates your way of being in the world - your knowledge - within larger systems of knowing&amp;rdquo; (p. 30). I&amp;rsquo;ve heard this sentiment in various forms through my education, but what underscored Wunker&amp;rsquo;s point for me was the reminder that situating yourself is intended to reveal, and account for, one&amp;rsquo;s myopias: the gaps in personal knowledge and experience that result in blind spots relating to other knowledges and experiences. In doing so, you are &amp;ldquo;opening yourself to the truth that you don&amp;rsquo;t have access to every experience&amp;rdquo; (p. 30). I love to think about the big questions of an archivally-minded life, many of which relate to the keeping of memory and therefore the rights and powers that surround that memory. Thinking and writing on these subjects is necessarily the subject of certain kinds of knowledge and experience, and it&amp;rsquo;s important for us archivists to remember that our views and approaches to archives may not be applicable to all situations, or even, understandable to people and communities that exist outside our own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, following Wunker&amp;rsquo;s example, here&amp;rsquo;s some information that will hopefully help situate me. I&amp;rsquo;m a cis-gendered, able-bodied man. I am white. English is my first language and my French is fair-to-middling. I was raised by middle-class parents, one of whom died when I was a teenager. I was born in New Brunswick, and lived there until I was 22, when I moved to Vancouver to pursue a MA in English. I lived there for 5 years. After the MA I enrolled in the Dual Master of Archival Studies and Master of Library and Information Studies degree program and graduated in 2015. I then moved to Toronto to be with my partner, and have lived in the city for nearly two years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;container&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://gehurley.github.io/img/ccarchives.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Charlotte County Archives&#34; align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;The Charlotte County Archives, where it all started. The fact that it is in a prison is incidental and not a metaphor for my career, hopefully (author photo).&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got into the world of archives through my very first real summer job at the Charlotte County Archives in Saint Andrews, New Brunswick. I was incredibly lucky to have happened upon this experience so early in my life. My high school history teacher was involved in the archives and had suggested I apply for a summer student position; I did and ended up working there for four summers. During that time, archivists Charlotte McAdam and Janice Fairney served as early mentors. I am deeply thankful for Charlotte&amp;rsquo;s early encouragement to think about the archival field as a career. The Charlotte County Archives remains the archetypal archival experience for me, though the institution itself is incredibly unique. The Archives was housed in a decomissioned nineteenth century prison made of huge slabs of grey granite. A set of original cells were made available for viewing to tourists. I learned how to do basic processing and description, helped visitors with research and reference, gave tours of the jail, and organized funraising lectures and a sleepover for local kids. One summer I even led a group of ghost hunters around the building in search of spirits (this might have to become a future blog post all to itself). It was all immensely fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, while I learned an enormous amount at this archives, and I&amp;rsquo;ve since worked in many archives and libraries as part of various practicum, co-op and contract placements during and after my education, my first experience in archives has become determinate of my understanding and approaches to archival organizations and practices since then. It&amp;rsquo;s become my classic use case (minus the ghosts), and one that I think of often in relation to some question or solution. So, both knowledge and experience, and a source of myopia as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, a big gap in my knowledge and experience is in technology. Even though I&amp;rsquo;ve spent most of my life playing with computers in various ways, I still feel like an outsider in the tech world because my education and learning in this area has always been ad hoc. I remain intimidated by its insider languages (both the words used to describe the work and the languages used to make it work). Part of this separation has been intentional. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to be a full-blown technologist necessarily - it&amp;rsquo;s another kind of myopia, I think, that is sometimes divorced from the ways in which technologies can be alienating, or their uses deterministic. I&amp;rsquo;m interested in the details of technologies that make be a better archivist, and more capable of preserving digital archives. I see my role as a translator, educator and collaborator in hopes of serving archivists and archives better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this little foray into self-situation (if I can call it that!) has been a good one. It&amp;rsquo;s by no means exhaustive, and never will be. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to know how much or little detail to include, or how relevant it could be to a reader, but I do think the exercise will help inform my thinking in posts here in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>