<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fixed on Grant Hurley</title>
    <link>http://www.granthurley.ca/fixed/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fixed on Grant Hurley</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 15:52:50 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.granthurley.ca/fixed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Grant Hurley | Résumé</title>
      <link>http://www.granthurley.ca/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 15:52:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.granthurley.ca/resume/</guid>
      <description>Current Role  Digital Preservation Librarian, Scholars Portal, Ontario Council of University Libraries/University of Toronto  Current Committee &amp;amp; Service Roles Canadian Association of Research Libraries (CARL), Digital Preservation Working Group (2017-present)
- Lead, Survey Subgroup
Canadian General Standards Board, Committee on Electronic Records and Image Management (2017-Present)
- Association of Canadian Archivists Representative (voting member)
Canadian Research Knowledge Network (CRKN) Trusted Digital Repository Task Group (2017-Present)
- Co-lead, Service Model and Certification Subgroup</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grant Hurley | Research</title>
      <link>http://www.granthurley.ca/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 08:48:30 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.granthurley.ca/research/</guid>
      <description>Research Interests: I am interested in a bunch of things relating to archives and libraries, including: making digital preservation accessible and actionable; digital preservation standards and certification; open government, open data, and citizen engagement; and subjects relating to archival theory and practice more broadly, such as community archives and decolonization.
Peer-Reviewed Articles Hurley, G. (2017). Your comments here: Contextualizing technologies, seeking records and supporting transparency for citizen engagement. Tidsskriftet Arkiv, 8(1), 1-25.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grant Hurley | About</title>
      <link>http://www.granthurley.ca/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 16:16:04 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.granthurley.ca/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello. I am an archivist and librarian. I work as the Digital Preservation Librarian for Scholars Portal, the information technology service for the Ontario Council of University Libraries. I am responsible for overseeing the preservation of shared licenced content content, such as journals and books, and developing, maintaining and supporting services to enable our members preserve their own unique digital assets. These include the Scholars Portal Trustworthy Digital Repository and the Permafrost digital preservation service, and developing new services in emerging areas to meet our members&amp;rsquo; needs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>