<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fixed on Grant Hurley</title>
    <link>https://www.granthurley.ca/fixed/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fixed on Grant Hurley</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 15:52:50 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.granthurley.ca/fixed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Grant Hurley | CV</title>
      <link>https://www.granthurley.ca/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 15:52:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.granthurley.ca/cv/</guid>
      <description>Current Role Current Committee &amp;amp; Service Roles
 Education Certifications Past Roles Past Committee &amp;amp; Service Roles Teaching Awards &amp;amp; Grants Student Roles  Current Role Canadiana Librarian, Thomas Fisher Rare Book Library, University of Toronto Libraries, Toronto, ON.
At the Fisher Library, I serve as the curator of our significant and extensive Canadian collections with a focus on primary sources and rare books documenting Canadian history and the literatures of Canada.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grant Hurley | Research</title>
      <link>https://www.granthurley.ca/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 08:48:30 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.granthurley.ca/research/</guid>
      <description>Refereed Articles Non-Refereed Articles Book Chapters Reports &amp;amp; Guides Proceedings Book Reviews Theses Conference Presentations &amp;amp; Posters Talks &amp;amp; Webinars Exhibitions &amp;amp; History Projects Other Writing  Refereed Articles Hurley, G. (2017). Your comments here: Contextualizing technologies, seeking records and supporting transparency for citizen engagement. Tidsskriftet Arkiv, 8(1), 1-25. doi: 10.7577/ta.1956 Hurley, G. (2016). Community archives, community clouds: Enabling digital preservation for small archives. Archivaria, 82, 129-150. Hurley, G.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grant Hurley | About</title>
      <link>https://www.granthurley.ca/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 16:16:04 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.granthurley.ca/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello! I am an archivist and librarian. My pronouns are he/him. I work as the Canadiana Librarian for the Thomas Fisher Rare Book Library at the University of Toronto. I also serve as a sessional instructor for the Faculty of Information at the University of Toronto for the course INF2403H: Digital Archives Workflows.
The work of stewarding library collections, both digitial and physical, is grounded on Indigenous lands. I am grateful to live on the traditional lands of the Huron-Wendat, the Seneca, and most recently, the Mississaugas of the Credit River.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>