<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Grant Hurley</title>
    <link>http://www.granthurley.ca/blog/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Grant Hurley</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 11:44:22 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.granthurley.ca/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes From the ACA Screening of Stories We Tell</title>
      <link>http://www.granthurley.ca/blog/notes-from-the-aca-screening-of-stories-we-tell/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 11:44:22 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.granthurley.ca/blog/notes-from-the-aca-screening-of-stories-we-tell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the recent ACA conference in Ottawa, I had the wonderful opportunity to host a screening of one of my favorite films - Sarah Polley&amp;rsquo;s 2012 documentary &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.storieswetellmovie.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stories We Tell&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve long been convinced that this film has a lot to say about archives. It’s a film fundamentally concerned with how we understand the past through the contradictions of memory and the opaque borders shared between memories and what has been recorded. The film weaves interviews and narratives with archival footage, documents and photographs into an engaging and emotional story that has so many layers, I find myself coming back to it again and again for inspiration and interest. And there is a fascinating twist that speaks in particular, I think, to archivists concerned with the boundaries of archives and how they are read and interpreted. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t seen the film, do so before reading further. Spoilers are imminent!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event came out of a paper proposal I had submitted about &lt;em&gt;Stories We Tell&lt;/em&gt; and Guy Maddin&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;My Winnipeg&lt;/em&gt; in response to the ACA conference call for papers. The paper didn&amp;rsquo;t fit with the rest of the conference program, alas, but host committee member Jenna Smith suggested an even better idea: screening one of the movies as a conference event. The screening was held on June 8th at the beautiful
&lt;a href=&#34;http://mayfairtheatre.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mayfair Theatre&lt;/a&gt; in Ottawa. The Mayfair is an independent, single-screen theatre and one of the last examples of such in Canada. It was a perfect venue for the film. All my thanks to the ACA host committee for setting this event up. I provided a bit of commentary and moderated the discussion, the notes from which I&amp;rsquo;ve edited below. You&amp;rsquo;ll find some interpolations based on the audience discussion in square brackets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Delightful movie screening of &amp;quot;Stories We Tell&amp;quot; tonight hosted by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/GrantHurley&#34;&gt;@GrantHurley&lt;/a&gt; with a great discussion afterwards. &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/ACA2017?src=hash&#34;&gt;#ACA2017&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/o81CiCBY8w&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/o81CiCBY8w&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Anna St.Onge (@deantiquate) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/deantiquate/status/872993458591604736&#34;&gt;June 9, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The detail that interests me most about &lt;em&gt;Stories We Tell&lt;/em&gt; is the reveal that happens close to the end when Polley shows the process of filming the set recreated family scenes using a Super 8 camera and actors made up to look very convincingly like her family members. Up to that point, she hasn’t been exactly candid about what aspects of the film are originals, such as footage from family sources depicting her real mother, and what parts have been recreated to mimic them. The first time I saw it, I was totally taken aback. Particularly as a first-time viewer, you’re taken along something of an emotional rollercoaster with a number of surprises along the way. And while the archivist-minded part of me was questioning the source of all of this footage – I remember thinking, “how was all of this filmed? Where did it all come from?” – I willingly suspended my disbelief for a while because the film encourages you to do so. [I was surprised to find that a good portion of the audience watching the film for the first time shared this experience. I often think of myself as kind of gullible, but apparently there&amp;rsquo;s something about the film itself (and the clever trickery that Polley uses to convince the viewer) that makes it difficult to tell the originals from the recreations.]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d like to suggest that Polley is doing something particularly interesting here regarding the use of archival materials in films. To begin, I want to distinguish between three main ways, as I see it, of representing archives and archival records on film.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, we’ve got the historic or dramatic recreation. This is the form we know best. It&amp;rsquo;s prevalent across lots of genres outside film, like in historic fiction. This is where archival research is used to inform dramatic events or characters’ actions. It gets the most explicit in the kind of TV true crime documentaries where it will say “dramatic reenactment” at the bottom of the screen just in case the audience doesn’t get it. These are performances that are based on archival records. Records informed them, but they are not directly visible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, we’ve got records that are presented in film as records; as evidence. This is where the filmmaker shows a clip or a photo or the like and it connects with the narration. Again, we see this all the time. Ken Burns is the master of this approach. His documentaries are often made up entirely of records.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;containerr&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://www.granthurley.ca/img/NFB-CityofGold.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot from City of Gold (dir. Wolf Koenig &amp; Colin Low, National Film Board of Canada, 1957)&#34; align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Screenshot from City of Gold (dir. Wolf Koenig &amp; Colin Low, National Film Board of Canada, 1957).&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this case, the filmmaker gathers and presents records to create a sense of performance. Ken Burns is famous for introducing motion into photographs in the classic zoom into photo to reveal some detail, an approach that is called the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ken_Burns_effect&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ken Burns effect.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; He has a remarkable talent for making static things seem more active and alive in his films. In fact, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.johnctibbetts.com/PDFs/City%20of%20Gold.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;he has cited&lt;/a&gt; a NFB film called &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nfb.ca/film/city_of_gold/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;City of Gold&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; as one of his inspirations. And – not to distract too much from the main point – this film was inspired by a collection of gold rush photos held at LAC. We saw this approach as well in the ACA conference’s first morning keynote, where filmmaker Ali Kazimi used a unique motion-based photo montage approach to illustrate his film &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nfb.ca/film/continuous_journey/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Continuous Journey&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, there is something in between: what Sarah Polley is doing in &lt;em&gt;Stories We Tell&lt;/em&gt;. She is recreating records in an imaginative way, but sticking within the boundaries of their archival qualities – their format and form – to lend them a sense of authenticity. The records are visible. But their form and format is the site of performance. These are performed records. And there’s a sense of trickery here to make it fairly difficult to distinguish between the originals and the recreated ones. It’s not entirely convincing to a critical eye, but it’s convincing enough to be fairly disorienting to the viewer. The film actually opens with one such recreated shot, so Polley is definitely priming the viewer to believe the authenticity of her recreations. And though I haven&amp;rsquo;t done the math, the recreations make up a fairly significant portion of the film.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what is Polley doing here? Well, on a basic level she’s able to fill out the narrative more. She is exploring the space between that which is recorded that that which is unknown, or known but unrecorded. And using recreated &amp;ldquo;archival&amp;rdquo; records to explore these boundaries. The interviews for the film were clearly made first, and sometimes the recreated records support the content of the interview; they make the claims seem more convincing. There’s a moment where one of her brothers talks about their mother’s hand – the hand waving “no!” – and the recreated version matches it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;containerr&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://www.granthurley.ca/img/Polley-StoriesWeTell-Screenshot-8.39.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot from Stories We Tell&#34; align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;A screenshot from Stories We Tell depicting the infamous &#34;hand&#34; - one of the recreated family movie records in the film. The shot occurs at 8:39.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of the recreated records convey moments of sadness that the more happy-go-lucky travel family reels don’t. But Polley does respect their content in a way that influences their blending. The recreated versions are not overly dramatic, and the actors generally act in similar ways to the originals: hamming for the camera, aware of its presence, kind of exposed in the harsh white light that was mounted on the top of those cameras. In this way, the originals and the recreated versions complement each other and blend together. They both influence the narrative. The originals are just as easy to read into the story. Looking at expressions and events in them that seem to support one perspective or another, so it’s not merely a matter of adding to the narrative so much as exploring beyond the limits of the records that have been left behind. You’ll notice as well that Polley has shot a lot of the modern scenes in Super 8 too. This is how she keys a smart viewer to the fact that something is going on. But they don’t have the same effect because their content doesn’t match their form. They are not performed in the same way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that Polley’s approach is intended to support some of the larger themes of the film. Just as she reveals the trick near the end, the narration notes the aspect of memory as having “shifts and fictions in them, mostly unintended.” And while her fictions are intended, they are all part of the slippery, difficult, and ultimately impossible problem of knowing her mother. Of getting close to the source and trying to understand the relationship between memory and truth, but seeing the source slipping away so one can &amp;ldquo;never touch bottom&amp;rdquo; as Harry notes in the film at one point. Polley’s approach speaks to how we read archival records. How quick we are to make a story by looking at documents and photographs collected together. And how easily such a story can be re-read, re-remembered and re-interpreted. [One audience member commented that she’d seen this movie once before, but that the re-watching added different layers of interpretation onto the film, a fact which seemed to support this idea at a meta-level!].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, there is the question of ethics and objectivity. Sarah Polley’s father Michael gets the closest to the heart of the film – more so than her biological father Harry – by questioning Sarah’s motivations. And by noting that her act of editing the film therefore makes it a product of her own views, rather than the objective work that contains the “whole picture,” as she says, that she might imagine she is creating. While Harry believes there is a truth to be found if one constructs the film in the right way (which he&amp;rsquo;d view as conforming to his version of the events), Michael understands that the exercise is less about finding some ultimate truth about Diane and more about the family’s various experiences trying to find her, to grieve her, and to remember and witness her life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t recall all of the wonderful points raised during the discussion that followed the screening because I was still a bit nervous up there. But there were some excellent ideas expressed in addition to the ones already inserted. Emily Lonie noted that she had actually seen the film before in the context of a book club, and a lot of the club’s members felt the film was narcissistic on the part of Polley, which I thought was interesting. I didn’t really feel this at all since the story is not really self-serving or demanding of sympathy. Though one of Polley’s sisters alludes to this potential reading in an early part of the film by wondering aloud why anyone would care about their family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Others were interested in exploring whether there really was an ethical breach present in the film’s reconstructions. To at least one person in the audience, they didn’t seem nearly as transgressive as it did to me. I think their perspective was that the recreations were more in line with typical dramatic representations, and therefore not attempting to deceive the viewer. I disagree, but I digress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I questioned the audience about the boundary between documentary and drama as well, particularly where the film is marketed as a documentary but is not necessarily as objective in its approach as is typical of the genre. I feel that Polley is exercising something of an ethical obligation through the “reveal” at the end where she is sitting in conversation with an uncanny duplicate of her mother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;containerl&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://www.granthurley.ca/img/Polley-StoriesWeTell-Screenshot-1.28.05.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot from Stories We Tell&#34; align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;A screenshot from Stories We Tell depicting Polley speaking to an actor playing her mother. The shot occurs at 1:28:05.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She certainly wasn’t obligated to inform the audience of her trickery, necessarily. But in doing so, it positions Polley as possibly atoning for the process of making it. Not only for the trickery, but also for the subjectivity  in its personal bias that Michael notes. The audience quite rightly noted the absence of Polley’s own voice from the film: she doesn’t reveal too much of herself or her own feelings in it and does not actively appear on camera. This absence mirrors the key absense of her mother from the film too. But where the mother haunts the film - either through the remaining archival records that document her life, or through her uncanny double - Sarah too haunts the film as its creator, commenting but never fully acknowledging her role in its making.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was so glad for the great attendance and lively conversation that followed the screening. Thank you to everyone who came out!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking &#39;Collaboration&#39; from Buzzword to Action: A Take on the AAO 2017 Conference</title>
      <link>http://www.granthurley.ca/blog/taking-collaboration-from-buzzword-to-action-a-take-on-the-aao-2017-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 21:06:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.granthurley.ca/blog/taking-collaboration-from-buzzword-to-action-a-take-on-the-aao-2017-conference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div id=&#34;containerr&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://www.granthurley.ca/img/aao-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;AAO conference plant disc&#34; align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;A conference swag item was this coaster with embedded flower seeds. Quite a nice metaphor, no?&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though I’ve been a volunteer for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aao-archivists.ca&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Archives Association of Ontario&lt;/a&gt; since late 2015, I finally had the chance to attend my first AAO conference last month at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B9VtQlWTv9MDR0FuT1pYVzhvazg/view&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Faculty of Information at the University of Toronto&lt;/a&gt;. I’d long heard that the AAO conference is one that is firmly devoted to archival practice, and this edition (the 14th since 2004!) only supported this notion. Most of the presentations I attended reflected on active projects or initiatives rather than working through the more arcane considerations of archival theory. For my part, I &lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B-BjI0FWqnSQNVdQcHR5dVZGZ0g2UzJ2RjZMTm82SkpheEZF/view&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;presented on Permafrost&lt;/a&gt;, a hosted digital preservation service I have been piloting with Lakehead University Library. Sara Janes, the University Archivist, was kind enough to attend and co-present on her experience with the pilot so far. The conference’s emphasis on field work over behind-the-desk theory has the advantage of making it more accessible, particularly to those not formally trained in the profession, but the downside is that it’s sometimes hard to link projects and initiatives back to the bigger concepts that inform them. Nevertheless, I think that there was an underlying ethos and set of ideas that connected many of the presentations, which I’m taking the chance to delve into a bit deeper in this space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conference theme was &amp;ldquo;Come Together: Meaningful Collaboration in a Connected World.&amp;rdquo; In my editorial for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://aao-archivists.ca/page-18317&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; Spring 2017 issue of Off the Record&lt;/a&gt;, I wrote that conferences such as this are a method of grounding the abstract idea of community in the real-life friendships and relationships that sustain that community. Though conferences are a fine way of exchanging information, their real value is the opportunity to meet and talk face to face. Seeing old friends and making new connections helps us invigorate our work and our sense of place and value in the archival community. Or they may just give us an occasion to compare problems, vent frustrations, gossip, and drink too much coffee. All have value. However, this idea presupposes that the community includes all those who should have a seat at the table (not to mention the ability to pay for the conference itself). What about individuals who are not yet part of the community and might not even know it exists? Or those that might be aware or interested, but do not feel enabled or are not funded to take part? Inquiries in this area formed a significant thread of the conference, I think. It was reflected in the title, of course; collaboration that is &amp;ldquo;meaningful&amp;rdquo; as opposed to obligatory or programmatic. “Collaborate” is often a buzzword deployed to make it seem like an organization is caring or connecting, but there may be no accountability for its realized impact. How can the archival community ensure collaborative efforts have actual positive effects? One key subject addressed by the conference was reconciliation with Indigenous peoples and knowledges in Canada, both as an archival community and within archival theory and practice. A second was the profession’s support for students. And there were several other presentations I had the chance to attend that also touched on similar themes of community-broadening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They keynote was delivered by Michael Etherington, Cultural Program Manager at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://ncct.on.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Native Canadian Centre of Toronto&lt;/a&gt; and a noted speaker. His talk was remarkably wide-ranging, touching on everything from international law and Indigeous governance to his personal experiences growing up in James Bay. His speaking method invited the audience into his own personal community: it was so engaging, intimate and conversational, it hardly felt like he was addressing a large room full of archivists. He challenged the audience to mature their relationships with Indigenous individuals and groups in their regions, including acquainting themselves with the treaties that cover the territory they live on, and to move beyond rote territorial acknowledgements and token Indigenous presence at events to more substantive involvement. He also addressed some of the awkwardness that comes with settler perceptions of Indigenous people, particularly despite good intentions. Obsessively struggling with terminology is one example. Rather than anxiously Googling &amp;ldquo;First Nations vs. Aboriginal vs. Indigenous???,&amp;rdquo; figuring out what the preference of the communities and/or individuals you wish to meet with is a good start. Or asking a living person wouldn’t hurt. Similarly, he mentioned how some overly cautious settlers worry that there&amp;rsquo;s some special protocol to speaking with an Indigenous person, when it&amp;rsquo;s only a shake of the hand, a friendly hello, and a willingness to listen and learn that&amp;rsquo;s necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of his closing comments related to the treaty covering his home community, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.archives.gov.on.ca/en/explore/online/james_bay_treaty/treaty.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;James Bay Treaty no. 9&lt;/a&gt;. He related the emotional experience he had when seeing this treaty in person for the first time. For the archivists he interacted with, he noted, it seemed like any other piece of paper, but to him and many members of his community, it is a fundamental document tracing their history and their rights. We hear about how important documents such as this are in the abstract all the time, but for me, hearing about this crucial kind of relationship between a document and the people whose rights it impacts was very affecting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just after the keynote, Sean Smith of the Archives of Ontario and Iona McCraith and Lisa Snider of the Archives Association of Ontario gave presentations on their own Indigenous-related outreach. Both have made efforts in this domain over the last year, with the AO working towards its Indigenous Relations Working Group and the AAO pulling together resources regarding reconciliation. Both noted, however, that substantive work is yet to come. For the AAO, one of the key issues is actually connecting with Indigenous community recordkeepers who could benefit from the services that the AAO provides and improving &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.archeion.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Archeion&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; description of Indigenous-related materials. For the AO, it means connecting more clearly with the communities that have an interest in records, seeking advice and feedback, and improving inclusivity. I spoke with Sean after his presentation on a question that&amp;rsquo;s been bothering me in this area: how much labour on behalf of an institution&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;engagement&amp;rdquo; strategy should be borne by the community the institution wants to engage with? It hardly seems appropriate to ask members of an Indigenous community, for example, to work with an institution without providing adequate resources to that community. Community members are busy enough supporting their own needs; an institution that says, &amp;ldquo;here come engage with us&amp;rdquo; has to provide resources to enable participants to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;containerl&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://www.granthurley.ca/img/aao-2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Raymond Frogner&#34; align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Raymond Frogner (right) delivering his plenary talk, moderated by John Roberts (left).&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, Raymond Frogner, Director of Archives at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://umanitoba.ca/nctr/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;National Centre for Truth and Reconciliation&lt;/a&gt;, gave an incredible plenary talk titled &amp;ldquo;Red Jenkinson: The Indigenous Influence on Modern Archival Practice.” His talk traced the role that &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/George_Hunt_(ethnologist)&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;George Hunt&lt;/a&gt;, a Tlingit consultant to the anthropologist Franz Boas and accomplish linguist and ethnologist himself, played in influencing postmodern archival theory. It was a fascinating talk, and one whose subtleties can&amp;rsquo;t be really borne out here with my scratchy notes from it, but I hope he intends to publish it. It also speaks to a larger question of making archival theory more hospitable to Indigenous knowledge practices, which may actually confirm or provide stronger support for existing strands of archival theory, just as it may also challenge its colonial origins, assumptions and myopia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The position of students interested in joining the profession was a second thread that relates to the theme of making our community more hospitable. Of course, all professionals were students of some kind at one time or another. However, the transition from student life to professional life is not always smooth, as students navigate contract work, sometimes for years, and may need to develop skills that aren’t covered by existing programs of study. (A common complaint I hear about is a lack of digital-oriented skills). The AAO has been working over the past year and a bit on improving student outreach, and I&amp;rsquo;ve had the pleasure of being part of this initiative. One of our accomplishments was pushing the student membership category into two years post-graduation to help mitigate loss of members due to financial precarity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was fantastic to see a number of student sessions at the conference. One I was able to attend featured a panel of students from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/ACAUofT/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ACA U of T student chapter&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://amiaatuoft.wordpress.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; Association of Moving Images Archivists Toronto&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/RyersonAMIA/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ryerson&lt;/a&gt; student chapters. The panel reviewed the ways in which student associations have been working together to share resources and improve training among themselves. Their challenges and concerns echoed a lot of the same ones we experience on the AAO board, such as how to model collaborative governance, how to find sources of stable funding, and how to attract (already overworked and busy) members. It was impressive to hear them describe juggling these issues and working through them as a group. It was also interesting to hear that student groups are finding that to attract members, they&amp;rsquo;re prioritizing professional development opportunities through workshops over social events like pub nights, which used to be the norm for these kinds of groups. It points to a potentially worrying trend where underfunded or unfunded student groups are trying to fill in gaps that professional programs should be covering. There&amp;rsquo;s also an opportunity for the AAO to fill in this gap - though this is not what the Association is really designed to do at this point. However, it is important that we continue to figure out ways in which the transition from student to professional can be supported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without burdening the post too much further, there were some other excellent presentations that tied into similar themes. Karen Milligan and Tracey Krause of the Hamilton Public Library presented on a new oral history initiative that is intended to broaden its reach beyond traditional participants. Danielle Robichaud and Krista McCracken &lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B-BjI0FWqnSQcXBQNVE4VkV2SG8/view?usp=sharing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;gave a great talk&lt;/a&gt; on using Wikipedia for archival activism by writing pieces on underrepresented people or communities and by promoting archival collections - both ways in which archives can see their mark made beyond the institution and hopefully make an impact in non-traditional ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many thanks to the AAO conference organizers (who were primarily made up of members of the Toronto Area Archives Group chapter) for putting on a fantastic event, and to the conference presenters for thoughtfully engaging with the theme. There were so many examples of grounding collaboration in thoughtful action - exactly what the AAO conference should be doing!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World &amp; Situating Myself</title>
      <link>http://www.granthurley.ca/blog/hello-world--situating-myself/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 16:02:31 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.granthurley.ca/blog/hello-world--situating-myself/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the tradition of &amp;lsquo;hello world&amp;rsquo; posts everywhere, I&amp;rsquo;d like to begin this blog by greeting anyone out there in internet land, particularly archives-and-libraries-on-the-internet-land. This blog is a place to hold my thoughts, to write out a problem or question that&amp;rsquo;s been nagging me, and to report on the successes and failures of my work. I&amp;rsquo;m especially interested in interrogating questions in archival theory and practice, and particularly, in digital preservation and related areas of study. I&amp;rsquo;m interested in lots of things relating to these fields, which you can find links to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.granthurley.ca/research/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently had the pleasure of reading Erin Wunker&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Notes from a Feminist Killjoy: Essays on Everyday Life&lt;/em&gt; (BookThug, 2016). In her introduction, Wunker describes the importance of accounting for one&amp;rsquo;s situated knowlege, an intention cited from scholar Donna Haraway. &amp;ldquo;Situating yourself enacts the deliberate practice of locating your own identity and experiences as coming from somewhere and being mediated by certain things such as your race, gender and class,&amp;rdquo; Wunker writes, &amp;ldquo;Laying these things out for yourself locates your way of being in the world - your knowledge - within larger systems of knowing&amp;rdquo; (p. 30). I&amp;rsquo;ve heard this sentiment in various forms through my education, but what underscored Wunker&amp;rsquo;s point for me was the reminder that situating yourself is intended to reveal, and account for, one&amp;rsquo;s myopias: the gaps in personal knowledge and experience that result in blind spots relating to other knowledges and experiences. In doing so, you are &amp;ldquo;opening yourself to the truth that you don&amp;rsquo;t have access to every experience&amp;rdquo; (p. 30). I love to think about the big questions of an archivally-minded life, many of which relate to the keeping of memory and therefore the rights and powers that surround that memory. Thinking and writing on these subjects is necessarily the subject of certain kinds of knowledge and experience, and it&amp;rsquo;s important for us archivists to remember that our views and approaches to archives may not be applicable to all situations, or even, understandable to people and communities that exist outside our own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, following Wunker&amp;rsquo;s example, here&amp;rsquo;s some information that will hopefully help situate me. I&amp;rsquo;m a cis-gendered, able-bodied man. I am white. English is my first language and my French is fair-to-middling. I was raised by middle-class parents, one of whom died when I was a teenager. I was born in New Brunswick, and lived there until I was 22, when I moved to Vancouver to pursue a MA in English. I lived there for 5 years. After the MA I enrolled in the Dual Master of Archival Studies and Master of Library and Information Studies degree program and graduated in 2015. I then moved to Toronto to be with my partner, and have lived in the city for nearly two years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;containerr&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://www.granthurley.ca/img/ccarchives.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Charlotte County Archives&#34; align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;The Charlotte County Archives, where it all started. The fact that it is in a prison is incidental and not a metaphor for my career, hopefully (author photo).&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got into the world of archives through my very first real summer job at the Charlotte County Archives in Saint Andrews, New Brunswick. I was incredibly lucky to have happened upon this experience so early in my life. My high school history teacher was involved in the archives and had suggested I apply for a summer student position; I did and ended up working there for four summers. During that time, archivists Charlotte McAdam and Janice Fairney served as early mentors. I am deeply thankful for Charlotte&amp;rsquo;s early encouragement to think about the archival field as a career. The Charlotte County Archives remains the archetypal archival experience for me, though the institution itself is incredibly unique. The Archives was housed in a decomissioned nineteenth century prison made of huge slabs of grey granite. A set of original cells were made available for viewing to tourists. I learned how to do basic processing and description, helped visitors with research and reference, gave tours of the jail, and organized funraising lectures and a sleepover for local kids. One summer I even led a group of ghost hunters around the building in search of spirits (this might have to become a future blog post all to itself). It was all immensely fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, while I learned an enormous amount at this archives, and I&amp;rsquo;ve since worked in many archives and libraries as part of various practicum, co-op and contract placements during and after my education, my first experience in archives has become determinate of my understanding and approaches to archival organizations and practices since then. It&amp;rsquo;s become my classic use case (minus the ghosts), and one that I think of often in relation to some question or solution. So, both knowledge and experience, and a source of myopia as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, a big gap in my knowledge and experience is in technology. Even though I&amp;rsquo;ve spent most of my life playing with computers in various ways, I still feel like an outsider in the tech world because my education and learning in this area has always been ad hoc. I remain intimidated by its insider languages (both the words used to describe the work and the languages used to make it work). Part of this separation has been intentional. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to be a full-blown technologist necessarily - it&amp;rsquo;s another kind of myopia, I think, that is sometimes divorced from the ways in which technologies can be alienating, or their uses deterministic. I&amp;rsquo;m interested in the details of technologies that make be a better archivist, and more capable of preserving digital archives. I see my role as a translator, educator and collaborator in hopes of serving archivists and archives better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this little foray into self-situation (if I can call it that!) has been a good one. It&amp;rsquo;s by no means exhaustive, and never will be. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to know how much or little detail to include, or how relevant it could be to a reader, but I do think the exercise will help inform my thinking in posts here in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>